The new morning we've finally found
やっと見つけた　新しい朝は
Yatto mitsuketa atarashii asa wa
is being hampered by the past.
月日が邪魔をする
Tsukihi ga jama wo suru
What we chased after wasn't the future,
向かう先は　「次」じゃなくて
Mukau saki wa tsugi ja nakute
but the past so full of remorse.
「過」ばかり追いかけた
Sugi bakari oikaketa
The ruthless memories won't stop playing;
鳴り止まない　容赦ない思い出たちは
Nariyamanai yousha nai omoide tachi wa
they won't be forgiving us for a long time.
許してくれそうにもない
Yurushite kuresou nimonai
It's about now that a teardrop
そろそろかな　手探り　疲れた頬を
Sorosoro kana tesaguri tsukareta hoho wo
beings to roll down my fatigued cheeks.
葛藤がこぼれ落ちる
Kattou ga koboreochiru
Will this rain ever stop?
雨は　いつか止むのでしょうか
Ame wa itsuka yamunodeshouka
I've been freezing for a long time.
ずいぶん長い間　冷たい
Zuibun nagai aida tsumetai
Why does the rain continue to fix on me?
雨は　どうして僕を選ぶの
Ame wa doushite boku wo erabuno
I wonder if it could embrace me.
包まれて　いいかな
Tsutsumarete iikana
Today, the rain falls again;
雨は　止むことを知らずに
Ame wa yamu koto wo shirazuni
endlessly it falls knowing no end.
今日も降り続くけれど
Kyou mo furitsuzukukeredo
We nestle close to each other to share the warmth
そっと　差し出した傘の中で
Sotto sashidashita kasa no naka de
under this umbrella, you gently held out to me.
温もりに　寄り添いながら
Nukumori ni yorisoinagara
It hurts...
痛い
Help me...
助けて…
I'm starving!
おなかすいた
Water...!
It hurts!
"Not yet finished experimenting"?
複数体の実験がまだだと
This in itself is the experiment!
これが実験だ
It was a success!
成功したのだ
The ultimate soldiers that never die, betray, and always fight according to our orders.
死なず　背かず
我々の命じるままに戦う
最強の兵士たち
An immortal army has been created!
不死の軍団の誕生だ
Pa...pa?
パ…パ
That's right!
そうだ　私がお前たちの父親だ
I am your father!
Now, listen closely to what I'm about to say.
いいか
これから言うことをよく聞け
Currently, there are several rebels targeting these headquarters!
目下　複数の反乱分子が
この司令部を狙っている
Papa!
パパ
You all are to-
お前たちは…
痛いよ…
Ouch...
That hurts.
痛い  痛い…
That hurts!
Pain!
That hurts...
痛いよ
Ouch...
It hurts...
The pain...
What a huge gate.
でけぇ扉だな
I don't like the feeling it gives off.
なんだかいやな空気だ
Is this really the place?
本当にここなのか
Yeah.
It looks exactly as Al described it.
アルから聞いたとおりだ
Who the heck is that?
こいつ何者だ
Number 66.
ナンバー６６
Barry the Chopper.
バリー·ザ·チョッパー
He was Slicer's partner.
スライサーの相棒だったヤツだ
このぉ
Open...!
Dammit...!
ちくしょ
How the hell are we supposed to open this?!
どうやって開けるんだ
Step aside.
どいてろ
It opened-
開い…た
Order the soldiers from Central that are fighting with the Briggs forces and Mustang to retreat.
ブリッグズ兵と
マスタングが戦っている
セントラルの兵士たちを
退かせるように言え
Oh? Are you going to shoot?
おっと　撃つ気か
Looks like your men aren't very disciplined.
部下のしつけがなっていないな
If you don't hurry up and have them retreat,
早く退かせないと
the soldiers from Briggs will continue to fight with no mercy.
ブリッグズ兵は遠慮なしに戦い続けるぞ
Wouldn't it bother you if you lost every single one of your soldiers?
兵を一人残らず失っていいのか
Shut the northern, southern, eastern, and western gates that allow entry into the Central Headquarters!
中央司令部
東西南北　すべての門を閉めろ
Don't let a single enemy force from Briggs or Mustang's party enter!
ブリッグズ兵　マスタングたち
一人として中に入れるな
So you're rotten, but it looks like you've still retained a set of testicles.
腐ってはいるが
根性なしではないようだ
Don't get too cocky, bitch!
調子に乗るな　女郎
I'll have all of you monkeys from Briggs crushed-
貴様らブリッグズの山猿どもなど
ひねりつぶして…
Huh?
あれっ　あっ　こっちか
Oh, this one.
You're not supposed to interfere.
邪魔  ダメ
I was told to defeat you.
倒せって言われた
What a drag...
めんどくせぇ
You've just created another spot for me at the top.
また一つ上の席が空いた
I thank you, Homunculus!
感謝するぞ　人造人間
You've saved me from having to stain this celebrated sword passed down in my family for generations!
我がアームストロング家に
代々伝わりし名刀に
うすら汚い血を
吸わせずに済んだわ
You-
野郎
They won't die?!
死なんだと
It hurts...
痛い…
I'm starving!
おなかすいた
It hurts!
痛い  痛い
The pain!
Brother!
お姉ちゃん
Don't tell me...!
まさか…
Did they attach souls to dolls?!
人形に魂のせてるのか
Dammit! There's no end to them!
くそっ　どんどん出てくるぞ
What the hell are these things?!
なんだ　こいつらは
知るか
Hell if I know!
Why aren't they dying?!
つうか　なんで死なねぇんだよ
This is bad.
まずいな
If we were to let them outside...!
こんなヤツらを外に出したら…
Did something happen?
なんかあったのか
No idea.
さあ
I heard Colonel Mustang pulled a coup d'etat.
マスタング大佐が
クーデター起こしたって話だぞ
How frightening.
物騒なこった
There, there. Don't cry.
よしよし　泣かないで
What do we do...
どうする…
You-
この
Oh no! They're getting out!
やべぇ　外に出る
My bad, I sealed off the exit.
悪ぃ　出口ふさいじまった
Don't worry about it.
気にすんな
If you hadn't done it, I would have destroyed the exit myself.
お前がやらなきゃ
オレが出口ぶっ壊してた
Now we can prepare for the worst!
これで腹もくくれるってもんだ
Okay, so now that we don't have to worry about them getting out...
さてと　外の心配もいらなくなったし
...let's show them what we've got!
あとはオレたちの腕の見せどころってか
It hurts!
痛い…
痛い
So much pain!
How dare they make something like this...!
こんなもんつくり出しやがって…
Guess we have to go through these guys first to give the old guy a beatdown.
ヒゲ野郎　ぶっとばすには
これ突破しなきゃならないのかよ
This is gonna be rough!
きっついなぁ
Mustang is currently escaping in an ice cream truck!
マスタングはアイスクリーム屋の
トラックで逃走中
Barricade the main roads!
主要道路を封鎖しろ
The truck may look normal,
but it's filled with weapons and ammo!
民間を装っているがトラックは
武器　弾薬を積んでいる
Don't let your guard down!
油断するな
A-A bear!
く…熊　モヒカン刈りの熊
A bear with a mohawk!
Signal lost.
切れた
A bear with a mohawk...?
モヒカン刈りの熊って　一体…
Captain Buccaneer from the Northern Army.
北方軍のバッカニア大尉よ
Colonel, it seems like it'll be difficult to enter the city.
大佐
市内に入るのは難しそうですね
Yeah.
そうだな
An ice cream truck, huh...?
アイスクリーム屋のトラックか…
I wonder if they're doing well.
野郎ども  うまいことやってるかな
But it's irritating that I can't fight alongside them.
しかし　戦力になれないってのは
歯がゆいな
I never knew how annoying it can be to wait.
待つだけっていうのが
こうもムズムズするもんだとは
I've been hearing this sound since yesterday.
この音　昨日からずっとだな
Hey Alphonse, what is that sound?
アルフォンス　なんの音だ
Selim's playing with my head.
セリムが僕の頭で遊んでるんだよ
He may be a monster on the inside, but I guess he's still a brat.
中身はあんなでも
しょせんはガキ…
Make him stop, Alphonse!
止めろ　アルフォンス
Make him stop those noises!
その音をやめさせろ
It's morse code!
トン·ツーだ　軍用の通信符号だ
Signals the army uses for communication!
He's telling someone our current location-
ヤツはここの場所を教え…
Hi.
Thanks for coming to pick me up, Kimblee.
お迎えありがとうございます
キンブリー
Seriously... please stop giving me extra work.
まったく　余計な仕事を
増やさないでください
Come on, give me a break.
大目に見てくださいよ
I won't let my guard down again.
もう油断しませんから
いや
なっ　なんですか　これ
W-What are these things?!
You tricked me, Envy!
だましたわね　エンヴィー
D-Did not!
うそなんか　ついて…
この奥に　不老不死…痛い
Immortality is just beyond-
Oww!
痛てて　痛ててててっ
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
このアマ
You bitch!!
Yes!!
やったぁ
Guess who's back?!
生き返った
Thanks for bringing me here, little brat.
ここまで連れてきてくれて
ありがとね
おチビちゃん
Why are there soldiers here?
軍人がなんでこんな所に…
立ち退き勧告でもしに来たのか
Are they here to make us leave?
Oh no... there's nowhere else to go.
困るわ
ほかに行く所もないのに…
W-What's this all about?
なっ　なんだぁ
まさか　我々の居場所が
Don't tell me they've found out where we're hiding...
かぎつけられたとかじゃ…
まずい　アルフォンス君が
Oh no, Alphonse!
Hang on, Doctor!
待てよ　先生
What if they found out you're Doctor Marcoh?!
あんたがドクター·マルコーだって
バレたらどうすんだよ
But I can't just sit back and watch...
しかし　黙って見ているわけには…
Take a moment to calm down.
落ち着けよ
If you were to be taken hostage,
it would only hurt Alphonse and the others.
あんたが人質にでもなったら
かえって　アルフォンスたちの
足枷になっちまうんだぞ
It's dangerous to just move around without thinking.
下手に動くのは禁物だ
おとなしくしてよう
Let's stay put.
Yeah? Yeah?
なっ　なっ
Are you alone?
一人ですか
I heard that Gluttony was here with you.
グラトニーも来ていると聞きましたが
I made use of him.
ヤツは私が頂いてしまいました
You ate him?
食べたのですか　仲間を
Your own comrade?
Not a comrade. We're part of the same being.
仲間ではありません
共同体です
We were born from the same father.
もとは同じ父上から生まれた身
Think of it as "coming back together", per se.
また一つに戻っただけのことです
I see.
そういうものですか
Mr. Heinkel!
ハインケルさん
Wow, you're still alive?
まだ　生きていましたか
Can't underestimate a chimera's survival power, after all.
さすがは合成獣
生命力が強い
Mr. Heinkel!
ハインケルさん
Dammit!
ちくしょう…うわっ　放せ
Let go!
I won't let you get away.
逃がしません
You-
この
Don't know when to give up, do you.
悪あがきを
逃げるな
Stop running away.
What?
何
I knew it wouldn't work.
やはり効かんか
That's as far as you're going to get,
Major General Armstrong!
そこまでだ  アームストロング少将
A shoot-on-sight order has been issued for your treason!
反逆罪により
貴官に銃殺命令が下された
Ready!
構え 撃て
Fire!
Idiot.
バカめ
Placing your men in this situation is just foolish.
この状況で兵をかためて置くな
Here's to hoping that did some damage to you...
少しはダメージをくらっててくれよ…
I've got you now.
捕まえた
Didn't get the wrong one this time.
今度は間違えない
Female general...
女将軍　殺す
...must die.
Sister!!
姉上
Are you all right?!
ご無事かぁ
Who are you even talking to, Alex?!
誰に物を言っている
アレックス
Glad to see you're safe.
ご健勝で何より
And so, what is that thing?
ところで　なんですかな　あれは
A Homunculus.
人造人間だ
A bullet isn't enough to even move him an inch.
鉄砲玉ぐらいではビクともせんぞ
大砲クラスで　ようやくだ
Maybe a little budge with a cannon.
Oh, my!
なんと
我が輩の得意分野ではありませんか
This is my specialty!
Please let your brother, Alex, handle this!
どうか　ここは
この弟アレックスにお任せを
Come, monster!
来い　化け物
めんどくせぇ
Such a drag...
Don't mind me...
オレに構うな…
Hurry up... and escape...
早く…逃げろ
No!
いやだ
ナマ言ってんじゃねぇ
Don't be stupid.
At this rate, neither of us will make it.
このままじゃ　共倒れだ
If you leave me behind, at least you may be able to survive.
オレを捨てていけば
お前だけでも助かるかもしれない
I said, no!
いやだって言ってるだろ
Focus on living for now!
余計なことを考えないで
生きることだけ考えて
Idiot!
バカ野郎
Take a good look at reality.
現実を見ろ　相手は
We're put against Kimblee and Pride.
あのキンブリーとプライドだぞ
Just leave me behind...!
オレのことは置いていけ…
Don't give up!
あきらめないでよ
I'll save you for sure!
僕が必ず助けるから
Dammit...!
くっそ
Move, stupid leg!
動け　この足
We can't lose here!
こんなところで
負けるわけにはいかないんだよ
僕たちは
Mr. Heinkel, hang onto me!
ハインケルさん　つかまって
Don't you dare give up!
あきらめないで
You siblings are so...
っとに お前ら兄弟は…
Why do you try to save others
when you're all damaged as well?
なんでてめぇもボロボロなのに
他人まで助けようとするんだ…
I made a promise.
誓ったんだ
I made a promise with Brother,
兄さんと誓ったんだ
that we won't let anyone die again.
もう誰も絶対死なせないって
You're right.
そうだな　生き残りゃ勝ちだって
I recall even Kimblee saying that "if you survive, you win."
キンブリーのヤツも言ってたっけ
Thanks to that, I remembered that I had something good with me.
お陰でいいもん持ってたこと
思い出したぜ
Why do you have this?
どうしてハインケルさんがこれを
I picked it up at the mines to the north after being abandoned by Kimblee...
北の炭鉱で　キンブリーに
見捨てられたときに拾った…
A philosopher's stone...
賢者の石…
We really may be able to beat them if we have this.
確かにこれがあれば
勝てるかもしれない
でも
But still!
Yeah, I know.
知ってる
This is made of human lives, right?
こいつは人の命で出来てるってんだろ
I've heard from your brother that you guys don't want to use this to return to your bodies.
元の体に戻るのに
これを使いたくないってのも
お前の兄貴に聞いた　だったら…
In that case...
In that case, use them to save the world; not for yourselves.
だったら　お前のためじゃなく
世界を守るために使ってやれ…
I'm asking you because you're willing to acknowledge them as human lives,
こんな石ころになってるのに
even after being reduced to such a state.
まだ　人の命として認めてる
お前だから頼むんだ
I can understand their feelings.
オレには分かる
No matter what they may look like now, they still want to fight to protect what's precious to them.
どんな見てくれになったって
大事なものを守るために
戦いたいんだよ
Give them a chance to fight too.
こいつらにも戦わせてやってくれ
Okay.
分かった
Give them a good beatdown,
ぶちかましてやれ
Alphonse.
アルフォンス
Yeah.
Let's fight them together.
一緒に戦おう
This cloud of dust is annoying.
うっとうしい土煙ですね
Should I blow it away with an explosion?
爆風で吹き飛ばしましょうか
No,
いえ
they're both still inside it.
まだ　二人とも土煙の中にいます
Besides, he won't be able to escape without his legs-
どだいあの足では逃げられ…
Oh, my.
これはこれは
Instead of escaping, you...
逃げるどころか…
Marvelous.
いい
Very entertaining, Alphonse Elric!
非常にいいですよ
アルフォンス·エルリック
Ever since that day passed,
あの日からずっと
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
泣かないと決めてきたけど
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
痛みを重ねても
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
何かを許せずにいた
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
もう戻れない
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
いくつもの日々
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
僕はまだ何もできずに
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
君のいた記憶の破片
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
またひとつ 消えてゆく
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
今日よりもっと
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
強くなりたい
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
この声がいつか届くように
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
歩き続けて
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
風が止んだら
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
君を探して空見上げるよ
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
夜明けの先に光がさすよ
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
虹がかかるよ
Niji ga kakaruyo
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
If it's a fight between man and man, choose the path you believe is right.
人と人との戦いならば
己の信じる道を行け
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
Only a fool would stand indecisive after being frightened at the thought of being soiled by the mud.
泥にまみれることを恐れ
躊躇するは愚の選択
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Fullmetal  Alchemist
第５２話　『みんなの力』
Episode 52, Combined Strength.
It is beyond the point of hesitation.
迷いのときはもう過ぎた